Garrett Haptonstall

2003 E. Veterans Memorial Blvd, Killeen TX 76051 Apt 4
Phone: 254-340-2906

Email: ghaptonstall@gmail.com

OBJECTIVE: To obtain a challenging position with opportunity for growth in all things. Personable and team oriented; works effectively with a wide range of personalities. Quickly learns job responsibilities and works well under pressure. Committed to continued education.

SOFTWARE EXPERIENCE:

- NodeJS
- RAID
- Vagrant \ Virtual Box
- Any form of Debian \ Red-Hat Linux
- Any form of Windows
- ESET NOD 32 Commercial AV
- Amazon AWS Services
- MySQL, PGSQL, SQL Server
- Subversion \ GIT \ BitBucket

- Google Cloud
- Eclipse IDE
- Wordpress
- Nginx & Apache2
- CISCO IOS
- SonicWall
- Ansible
- VPN Technology

I have worked with these and many, many more commercial, open source, and private enterprise software's. My experience goes from basic technical support, systems administration, programming and development, on to network engineering and IT / project management. I am a "hands on", very diverse, all around IT professional and am always looking to expand my knowledge on doing what I love to do!

PROGRAMMING EXPERIENCE:

These are all programming languages that I am currently *FLUENT* with:

- NodeJS & E6
- JavaScript, jQuery, nextJS
- PHP5
- Perl, CGI

- Java & Java for Android
- ReactJS & Typescript,
- HTML5, CSS3, Markdown
- SOL PSOL MYSOL

I've developed relational database driven applications and web sites using a LAMP stack, I have also developed DB driven apps using a Node JS and Nginx web stack and have configured / administrated both. Programming languages that I have developed with include JavaScript, jQuery, Perl, SQL, Java, PHP, CSS, XML, CGI, HTML, AJAX and XSL. Experience developing utility and network applications with Java for Android smart-phones and tablets. I have also configured and maintained services such as LDAP, FTP, SSH, NTP, DNS, Named, SendMail, Postfix and Tomcat. I have knowledge of most networking protocols, ticketing and POS systems (MICROS), configuring routers with all security types, static \ dynamic IP's, domains and virtual private servers, Firewalls such as IP-Tables / Chains, and the Cisco IOS.

COMPUTER / HARDWARE EXPERIENCE:

I worked with, installed, configured, and maintained CISCO 3750x 24port POE and 48 port switches, CISCO 4400 VPN Routers. Installed and configured ThinkMate 8Tb storage Network Video Recording systems and SuperMicro 32 core Servers with ubuntu 10.04 server edition all with RAID, NFS, Heartbeat and Interface Bonding. I have installed and maintained a variety of hardware including commercial grade projectors, FitPC2's, ION's, and Alcorn Bin-loop's / players. I have installed a variety of rack mount systems and use professional cable management, I can also punch down and cap CAT5, CAT6 \ 6E, and other common Ethernet \ fiber interfaces.

WORK EXPERIENCE:

Private Consulting and Training

From May 2016 to current day.

Work as private consultant under my own entity, taking on freelance projects and small contracts doing various IT jobs. Web development, Android development and Linux systems administration. I also have performed stress testing, load balancing and penetration testing for clients. Personal projects include tdella.com and GUI (Guerrilla UI).

SHINDiiG LLC - Suaray

60 S Stephanie St # 110, Henderson, NV 89012 from June 2015 to March 2016,

Worked as lead mobile developer for the mobile app SUARAY, which is an event finder & social platform. The main technology used for mobile app was AngularJS allowing us to compile both Android and IOS applications. The RESTful API was built in PHP and I would add functionality and routes when needed. Being a senior member of development team I would often suggest structure and API enhancements as well as many Administration upgrades. I was trusted with maintaining and fixing issues with network, databases, and servers which controlled the Suaray website, API, and automated emailing. I eventually reworked the Android app to be fully native Java implementing the Google Material design. Would often provide assurances to the business and other key stakeholders that the applications being enhanced, modified or developed were in the best interest of the deliverable's and objectives set for in the business requirements.

Moshyn Inc. -- Moshyn.com

9960 W Cheyenne Ave. Suite 290 Las Vegas, NV 89129 from April 24, 2014 to Present. Working with this small startup I have developed and continue to work on many useful web and phone applications. I helped build full stack software which includes websites with backend, iPhone applications, and I personally built the Android applications for our software's. Being a digital agency we took many contracts for other big name clients such as Worldpokertour.com, setting up their entire AWS infrastructure which included setting up an RDS, EC2, Auto Scaling, Elastic Load Balanced stack. Some of the projects we are releasing and working on include Pijun, a bug tracking system and API backed by AWS, LoopSale, a community search engine to help find and sell items and services in local areas. I also administrate all our servers and any of our clients servers.

SearchCore, LLC -- Manufacturedhomes.com

<u>26497 Rancho Pwky S, Lake Forest, CA 92630 from June 10, 2013 to April 24, 2014.</u> Worked as lead developer under the company CTO with a team of graphic designers and programmers to build a manufactured / modular home finder website with a full user backend and employee backend.

<u>Manufacturedhomes.com</u> is live and uses geo-targeted technology to find homes in the users area. We built it using Node JS and Nginx with an AWS infrastructure to back external resources such as images via S3 and EC2 instances. The site includes tools for both users, manufactured home dealers, and company employees to manage floor plans, dealers, manufactures, communities, mortgage calculators, documents, calendar and many more. The site continues to grow today and happy clients includes many big name manufactures such as Kabco Builders, Magnolia Homes, and KIT Home Builders.

Business Development Institute, LLC

1091 S Cimmaron Rd. Suit A, from January 24, 2012 to May 24, 2013.

Senior Programmer & Network Administrator. I managed over 15 Linux servers both Red-Hat and Debian, Windows 2008 Domain server, VM server, and VOIP / PBX servers that combined together into a complex intranet system that governed this Internet SEO sales company. I have developed company websites built in various PHP frameworks including Zend, Kohana, Wordpress, Drupal, and CakePHP. I also maintain and added onto the original system built in a custom PHP framework which included original company sites and main Administration system. As lead programmer I managed one other software developer and IT technician and administrated over 50

end-users. I managed projects in a team based environment and managed all software, source code, and applications using version control via Subversion. I performed a variety of tasks on a daily bases such as setting up new servers when old ones would fail, replacing computer and server hardware, basic troubleshooting for user workstations, maintain online reputation and made sure all employee workstations stayed free from viruses and malware.

Murder Inc. / Eagle Group Holdings, LLC

PO Box 97811 Las Vegas NV 89193, Tropicana Hotel, from January 3, 2011 to September 19, 2011. Linux Systems Administrator. Managed 3 IT technicians' and Administered over 30 users in the construction of the Las Vegas Mob Experience. Designed and Configured the entire network infrastructure from scratch, including creating the development and test environment to conduct testing on the database driven application. I would analyze network overhead and resolve any issues to free up bandwidth. Configured the Cisco IOS software with multiple V-Lan's to handle network load balance. Installed and maintained over 500 devices and connected them over a 4GB fiber optic back-bone to a centralized system, all within the deadlines set by my superiors. Installed and Configured tools such as PHPpgadmin, Bugzilla, MICROS and Nagios. I also have experience in configuring Email servers, DNS, NTP, Ldap / Active Directory, SAMBA, Point To Point / Gateway VPN's, and using monitoring systems such as WireShark, Nagios, and Nessus.

EDUCATION

Grapevine High School, 2001-2005 Grapevine TX Stephen F. Austin State University, 2005-2006 Nacogdoches TX, General Business Major IT University Online, 01/2013 - Current, CCNA Course (Cisco Certified Network Analyst)